

Hitesh Ramani

Nationality: Indian

(+91) 8320563229

Date of birth: 16/11/1994

Gender: Male

■ Email address: ramanihiteshc@gmail.com

Website: http://ramanihiteshc.blogspot.com/

○ Whatsapp Messenger: 8320563229

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ramanihitesh/

Github: : https://github.com/ramanihiteshc

• Address: 67, Gokuldham Society Chhaprabhatha, 394107 Surat (India)

ABOUT ME

Software Engineer with around 4+ years of experience in the full mobile development life cycle for Apple mobile devices. Experienced iOS Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. I know development in most iOS Framework in all iOS layers (Cocoa Touch, Media, Core Services, and Core OS). Proven skills in app development and maintenance, client interaction, and team management, Taking responsibility. And currently learning React-Native for mobile App Development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

iOS Application Developer

Escrow Infotech [05/01/2017 - 13/06/2017]

City: Surat
Country: India

- Work to create new applications and to expand/improve on an ongoing basis by adding new functionality and resolving existing issues.
- Provide technical leadership and take ownership for the technical development project/program delivery of component design, development, and maintenance, maintain technical components and templates.
- Worked with other developers, designers, and product/business managers to develop new features consistent with the product roadmap. Worked with a team that developed and distributed an iOS App on the App Store
- $^{\circ}$ Worked with quality assurance team to confirm app compatibility with analogous solutions on other platforms.
- $\,^\circ\,$ Designed user experience frameworks applicable to multiple screen sizes, including both iPad and iPhone.
- Ported existing applications from Android to iOS, adapting software to meet unique parameters.
- Applied Agile software development methodology to elevate final products and streamline development efforts.
- Applied Apple's Swift development language to code native apps for the iOS platform.
- Complied with all Apple App Store guidelines to provide rapid approval and deployment to retail channels.
- Maintained existing mobile applications by designing patches to be applied via iOS automatic updates.

iOS Swift developer

Beetonz Infotech [10/07/2017 - 20/03/2020]

City: Surat
Country: India

- Integrated existing third-party APIs and frameworks Firebase tools, Twilio, Google APIs, Quick, and a few others.
- Wrote code snippets, extensions scripts and performed code reviews for daily maintenance activities., Learned Swift and started working on individual projects
- Gained brief knowledge about Custom keyboard, sticker packs, iPhone Extensions, Watch kit apps.
- Worked with quality assurance team to confirm app compatibility with analogous solutions on other platforms. Designed user experience frameworks applicable to multiple screen sizes, including both iPad and iPhone.

Project manager

Darkswift Infotech [15/06/2020 - Current]

City: Surat Country: India

- Maintained effective staff and resource utilization rates to balance financial and operational obligations.
- Developed key operational initiatives to drive and maintain substantial business growth.
- Met dynamic needs by keeping internal systems scalable and highly responsive.
- Prepared organization for forecasted demand levels through effective operational planning.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Gujarati

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Cooking, Farming

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Saurashtra university [16/07/2012 – 14/05/2015]

Address: Saurashtra University Campus, Munjka, 360005 Rajkot (India)

https://www.saurashtrauniversity.edu/

MCA

RK University [16/07/2015 – 30/12/2016]

Address: Bhavnagar Highway Kasturbadham, 360020 Rajkot (India)

https://rku.ac.in/

DIGITAL SKILLS

Adobe In Design and Photoshop / Adobe Illustrator / digital Marketing / Social Marketing / Writing blogs